onthe.io 2019-07-01

# Privacy policy | IO Technologies

#### 1\. Introductory statement

The privacy and confidentiality of your personal data is a top priority for IO Analytics (“IO”). This privacy policy governs the manner in which IO processes personal data obtained from its website users. By using our website, providing us with your personal data, and reading this policy: 

  * you declare your consent for us processing your personal data for contacting purposes;
  * you declare your consent for us processing your personal data for internal administrative reasons; and you are deemed notified of such processing. 
  * If you do not agree with the processing of your personal data, please do not provide us with your personal data via the IO website.

#### 2\. The personal data we may collect and how we may use it

We only collect personal data from you that is necessary for us to allow you to utilize our IO website. Examples of personal data that we may collect from you are the following:

  * full name;
  * record of communication;
  * email;
  * phone number and location.

We keep a record of your communication with us to address potential issues you might face. We may use your email address to inform you about our services, changes or improvements. When using our website, we may collect the following information about you:

  * information about your computer;
  * login information;
  * the frequency and duration of your website visits;
  * information about searches made on our website;
  * internet protocol address and cookies;
  * pages you visit on our site.

All of the above collected information is used for organizational, administrative and internal reasons. We do not provide this information to third parties, except as required by law.

The IO website is not directed at children under the age of 16 and does not knowingly collect any personally identifiable information from children under the age of 16.

#### 3\. How we collect your personal data

We use cookies, web beacons, tags and scripts, and other similar technologies including local storage objects such as HTML5. These technologies allow us to manage access to and use of the IO website, recognize you and help us understand how you use our website.

Cookies are files or pieces of information that may be stored on your computer (or other devices, such as smartphone or tablet) when you visit IO website. This allows us to distinguish your device from those of other users of our website. A cookie will usually contain the name of the website the cookie has come from, how long it will stay on your device, and a randomly generated unique id number.

We use the following types of cookies:

**Persistent cookies.** We use persistent cookies to improve your experience of using the IO website.

**Session cookies.** Session cookies are temporary and removed at once from your device after your web browser closes. We use session cookies to help us track the internet usage as described herein.

You may refuse to accept cookies by changing the corresponding settings in your web browser. However, if you choose to do so, you might be unable to access certain content of the IO website. Unless you change your web browser settings regarding cookies, our systems will place cookies on your device when you visit our website.

#### 4\. Main purposes of processing

We use your personal data for the following purposes:

  * to personalize the user experience;
  * to operate, provide, improve, and maintain our website and services;
  * to respond to your inquiries and for other customer service purposes; and
  * for other administrative and internal business purposes.

#### 5\. Security of your personal data

IO uses a variety of security measures to keep your personal data protected from unauthorised access and disclosure. IO has in place a security system that is fully compliant with the EU General Data Protection Regulation (the “GDPR”). IO processes your personal data, e.g., based on the following principles:

  * **Fairness and lawfulness:** we process your personal data only after obtaining your consent for the processing, and for a determined specific purpose;
  * **Transparency:** we process your personal data in a transparent manner, and only with your knowledge;
  * **Purpose limitation:** your personal data is processed within the purposes outlined above;
  * **Data minimization:** we only process your personal data to the extent that it is actually needed to achieve the processing purposes;
  * **Accuracy:** we ensure that your personal data is accurate and kept up to date;
  * **Storage limitation:** your personal data will be processed for the limited period of 5 years, if no other contractual obligations with you allow a longer time period;
  * **Integrity and confidentiality:** we secure your personal data with suitable organizational and technical measures; and
  * **Accountability:** we will be responsible for, and be able to demonstrate compliance with the above- mentioned principles.

#### 6\. Access to your personal data

Only a limited number of IO employees who are responsible for the maintenance of our website and for customer relations have access to your personal data.

#### 7\. Main processing actions with your personal data

We may process your personal data mostly by way of collection, storing, recording and structuring. However, we cannot exclude other ways of data processing, if necessary for the above-mentioned purposes.

We may also transfer your personal data from the European Economic Area (the “EEA”) outside the EEA (e.g., from our servers located in Germany and the Netherlands to our offices in Ukraine). If we do so, we reasonably ensure that your rights and freedoms as a data subject are protected in compliance with the GDPR.

#### 8\. Where we store your personal data

All your personal data collected by us is stored on our secure servers located in Germany and the Netherlands.

#### 9\. Disclosure of your personal data

We use our best efforts not to disclose any confidential information to third parties. The IO website maintains a secure site, but you should know that computer use may be monitored by third parties such as network administrators, employers, internet providers, and operation system & internet browser vendors, and, thus, we cannot guarantee the security of information you post online. You disclose all information online at your own risk. Please remember that this website may be hosted outside your home country, and your email communications to us may be directed to a server that is hosted outside your home country. Communications over the Internet may not be secure.

#### 10\. Third party provided content/links

Users may find content and products of other companies or organizations on our website and/or links to the sites and services of our suppliers, licensors, or other third parties. Please note that we do not control these sites. Each such third party is solely responsible for complying with the laws, rules and regulations applicable to its business and the operation of its own website.

#### 11\. Your privacy rights

If the GDPR is applicable for you, you may have the following data subject rights:

  * the right to obtain any information about processed personal data;
  * the right to access your personal data;
  * the right to withdraw your consent for processing of your personal data;
  * the right to correct and erase your personal data;
  * the right to be aware of any correction or erasure of your personal data, restriction of processing, and recipients of your personal data;
  * the right of data portability;
  * the right not to be subject to a decision based solely on automated processing; and
  * the right to lodge a complaint with a competent data protection authority.

For any questions regarding your personal data please feel free to contact IO’s Data Protection Officer at Den Golotiuk (den@iotechnologies.com).
